National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Video, 1985-2005; nam_apap298-8; 5.40 cubic ft.
  Recorded VHS and DVD video of television programs, films, and other programs relating to capital punishment in the United States. Many of the items featured members of the NCADP, particularly Steven Hawkins, the former Executive Director
  - 12 Minutes, a Raymond A. Thomas Film, 2001; nam_apap298-8_1 (Vhs 1)
  - 14 Days in May (execution of Edward Earl Johnson, Undated; nam_apap298-8_2 (Vhs 2)
  - 48 Hours: "Willie Otey" Hanging of Wesley Allen Dodd in Washington State, 1993; nam_apap298-8_3 (Vhs 3)
  - 48 Hours: Juveniles and the Death Penalty, Undated; nam_apap298-8_4 (Vhs 4)
  - 60 Minutes: Inmate 777, 1997 December 7; nam_apap298-8_5 (Vhs 5)
  - About the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty in German, 1999; nam_apap298-8_6 (Vhs 6)
  - ACLE "Juvenile Justice: Unplugged" a field exploration by and for students, 1997; nam_apap298-8_7 (Vhs 7)
  - Alabama Coalition Speakers Bureau Training - Dennis Balskem Esq. speaks for the Alabama Coalition, 1986; nam_apap298-8_8 (Vhs 8)
  - America's Black Forum Show #PR1-99/00-13R "Capital Punishment Debate", 1999 November 3; 2000 June 18; nam_apap298-8_9 (Vhs 9)
  - America's Black Forum Show #PR1-99/00-13R "Capital Punishment Debate", 1999 November 3; 2000 June 18; nam_apap298-8_10 (Vhs 10)
  - America's Black Forum Show #PR1-99/00-13R "Capital Punishment Debate" Race Issues, 1999 November 3; 2000 June 18; nam_apap298-8_11 (Vhs 11)
  - American Bar Association - Executing Injustice: ABA Call for a Moratorium on Executions, Undated; nam_apap298-8_12 (Vhs 12)
  - American Forum, Hurricane Advisory: Popular Culture and Capital Punishment, Undated; nam_apap298-8_13 (Vhs 13)
  - Amnesty Death Penalty, Undated; nam_apap298-8_14 (Vhs 14)
  - Amnesty International USA "Campaign Against the Death Penalty", Undated; nam_apap298-8_15 (Vhs 15)
  - Amnesty International USA "The Next Step", Undated; nam_apap298-8_16 (Vhs 16)
  - Amnesty International USA "The Next Step", Undated; nam_apap298-8_17 (Vhs 17)
  - Balancing Justice and Mercy: a group of law officials and others discussing the criminal justice system and capital punishment, Undated; nam_apap298-8_18 (Vhs 18)
  - Balancing the Scale: Robert Gilliand, 1989 March 15; nam_apap298-8_19 (Vhs 19)
  - Balancing the Scales - The Texas Moratorium Network, Undated; nam_apap298-8_20 (Dvd 1)
  - Odell Barnes Defense, 2000 January 15; nam_apap298-8_21 (Dvd 2)
  - Odell Barnes Defense, 2000 January 15; nam_apap298-8_22 (Vhs 20)
  - BET - talk with Tavis Smiley: Steven Hawkins along with Busisiwe Chabeil and Chokwe Lumumba, discuss the case of Azi Kambule, Undated; nam_apap298-8_23 (Vhs 21)
  - BET - talk: Steve Hawkins, Executive Director of NCADP, interviews with Tavis Smiley, 1997; nam_apap298-8_24 (Vhs 22)
  - The Benefits of Representing Capital Defendants Developing Mitigation Claims: Bryan Stevenson discusses the benefits of representing capital defendants. Many Welch discusses how to develop mitigation claims, 1993 June 8; nam_apap298-8_25 (Vhs 23)
  - "Better Off Dead": Lifetime movie dealing with murder and the death penalty, 1992 December 11; nam_apap298-8_26 (Vhs 24)
  - William Brennan Project: Interviews & News Conference & Program, raw footage, Undated; nam_apap298-8_27 (Vhs 25)
  - Walter Brooks Show: Steve Hawkins interviews with Walter Brooks to discuss his life as an attorney, 1996 May 3; nam_apap298-8_28 (Vhs 26)
  - Bush's Deadly Ambition, produced & directed by Micki Dickoff and Tim Tale, Correspondent: David Smith - Channel 4/London, 2000; nam_apap298-8_29 (Vhs 27)
  - CBS News "Before Your Eyes/One Last Chance" 92:00, 1996 July 23; nam_apap298-8_30 (Vhs 28)
  - CBS Program - William Andrews questions the racial inequalities that surround the death penalty in the US, Undated; nam_apap298-8_31 (Vhs 29)
  - Campaign Against the Death Penalty: Amnesty International's campaign to end the death penalty 29:30, Undated; nam_apap298-8_32 (Vhs 30)
  - Campaign Against the Death Penalty: Footage from Amnesty International's campaign to end the death penalty 29:30, Undated; nam_apap298-8_33 (Vhs 31)
  - Children's Crusade to Death Row - Plough Publishing, 1997 August 18-20; nam_apap298-8_34 (Vhs 32)
  - Client: Steven Hawkins, Topic: Morning News - Death Penalty / Delaware, 1996 November 22; nam_apap298-8_35 (Vhs 33)
  - Cochran and Grace "Death Penalty": Steven Hawkins, Executive Director of NCADP, as well as others discuss capital punishment in America, 1997 January 21; nam_apap298-8_36 (Vhs 34)
  - Court-TV - A close look at the case of Lloyd Schulp, 1995 June 21; nam_apap298-8_37 (Vhs 35)
  - Court-TV "Chance & Powell: Back in the World", Undated; nam_apap298-8_38 (Vhs 36)
  - Court-TV On Appeal Show #32, Jones v. Butterworth, 1997 December 29; nam_apap298-8_39 (Vhs 37)
  - CRLS - Defining the Future [marked "not playing"], Undated; nam_apap298-8_40 (Vhs 38)
  - Crossfire Sunday: Steven Hawkins joins a distinguished panel to debate the death penalty, 1997 June 8; nam_apap298-8_41 (Vhs 39)
  - Governor [Mario] Cuomo Death Penalty Speech at CSR, 1989 March 13; nam_apap298-8_42 (Vhs 40)
  - Current Issues - Capital Punishment: Leigh Dingerson, Richard Stamp, and students discuss and debate the death penalty, 1992 May 2; nam_apap298-8_43 (Vhs 41)
  - Willie Darden - 20/20: the case of Willie Darden, 1988 January; nam_apap298-8_44 (Vhs 42)
  - De Press Conference, Undated; nam_apap298-8_45 (Vhs 43)
  - Debate on the Death Penalty: Both opponents and experts debate the moral and constitutional factors of the death penalty in the United States, 1988 October 4; nam_apap298-8_46 (Vhs 44)
  - Deadline: a film by Katy Chevigny and Kirsten Johnson [commercial DVD release], 2004; nam_apap298-8_47 (Dvd 3)
  - Deadline - Sundance Version, 2004; nam_apap298-8_48 (Vhs 45)
  - Deadline - Texted Letterbox, 2004; nam_apap298-8_49 (Vhs 46)
  - Death Penalty Advocates, directed by Jesse Limbaugh, Undated; nam_apap298-8_50 (Vhs 47)
  - The Death Penalty in Alaska? Never Again: Alaskans explain why the death penalty was abolished in their state, Undated; nam_apap298-8_51 (Vhs 48)
  - The Death Penalty: Albany Law School, 1991 April 5; nam_apap298-8_52 (Vhs 49)
  - The Death Penalty: Albany Law School, 1991 April 5; nam_apap298-8_53 (Vhs 50)
  - The Death Penalty: Albany Law School, 1991 April 6; nam_apap298-8_54 (Vhs 51)
  - The Death Penalty: Albany Law School, 1991 April 6; nam_apap298-8_55 (Vhs 52)
  - "The Death Penalty: Justice or Revenge?" - WEDU Tampa, Tom Mills, Producer, 1990 July 20; nam_apap298-8_56 (Vhs 53)
  - Death Penalty Rally - Albany, NY Rough Cuts Camera #1, 1989 May 23; nam_apap298-8_57 (Vhs 54)
  - Death Penalty - University of Glasgow Media Services, Undated; nam_apap298-8_58 (Vhs 55)
  - Death Row Friends - 20/20, 2000 August 18; nam_apap298-8_59 (Vhs 56)
  - Delaware Tonight, 2003 June 5; nam_apap298-8_60 (Vhs 57)
  - Francis Dunnery - Live in New York City: An excerpt from Francis Dunnery's current album, Undated; nam_apap298-8_61 (Vhs 58)
  - The Empty Chair - Four Stories: Murder Victims' Families Confront Loss & Punishment, 2003; nam_apap298-8_62 (Vhs 59)
  - The Execution of Raymond Graham - ABC TV Movie, Undated; nam_apap298-8_63 (Vhs 60)
  - The Execution of Raymond Graham: A made for TV movie that spans the last hour of an inmate who is executed by lethal injection, Undated; nam_apap298-8_64 (Vhs 61)
  - Execution of David Lawson - Donahue Special Report, Undated; nam_apap298-8_65 (Vhs 62)
  - Executions: a first hand look at executions past and present all over the world, 1995; nam_apap298-8_66 (Vhs 63)
  - Eye for an Eye?: This film examines the social injustices of the death penalty in America and in Texas, 1988 August 1; nam_apap298-8_67 (Vhs 64)
  - Barry Fairchild - 20/20 News: Story of the Barry Fairchild Case. Strong accusations of police misconduct and how that can lead to a wrongful conviction, 1991 March 29; nam_apap298-8_68 (Vhs 65)
  - Finding a Way: New Initiatives in Justice for Children, 1997; nam_apap298-8_69 (Vhs 66)
  - Final Judgment: A documentary about the death penalty, Undated; nam_apap298-8_70 (Vhs 67)
  - Firing Line Debate - PBS: Death penalty experts debate this issue, Undated; nam_apap298-8_71 (Vhs 68)
  - First Tuesday Death Row - A One Women Band: The Story of Marie Dean, a abolitionist who works alone to find representation for death row inmates in Virginia, 1986; nam_apap298-8_72 (Vhs 69)
  - First Tuesday Death Row - A One Women Band: The Story of Marie Dean, a abolitionist who works alone to find representation for death row inmates in Virginia, 1986; nam_apap298-8_73 (Vhs 70)
  - Florida Crossroads "Female Prison Rates": Cindy Smith of FPTV visits Florida's Death row to interview Andrea Hicks Jackson, one of the five women on death row in Florida, Undated; nam_apap298-8_74 (Vhs 71)
  - Fox News - Shareef Cousin case, WVUE, 1999 January 8-9; nam_apap298-8_75 (Vhs 72)
  - Fox News: Features Krista Pike, the youngest person on death row, Undated; nam_apap298-8_76 (Vhs 73)
  - Fox News: Steven Hawkins is interviewed about the Timothy McVeigh Trial, 1997; nam_apap298-8_77 (Vhs 74)
  - Fox News: Steven Hawkins and former US Attorney Joseph Digenova discuss the imposition of the death penalty of juveniles involved in a gang related shooting in SE, Washington, D.C., Undated; nam_apap298-8_78 (Vhs 75)
  - John Wayne Gacy Execution - Media Coverage, 1994 May; nam_apap298-8_79 (Vhs 76)
  - John Wayne Gacy Execution - Media Coverage, 1994 May; nam_apap298-8_80 (Vhs 77)
  - John Sterling Gardner, Jr.: A Case Study of how to recognize child abuse and neglect and intervene Effectively: This discusses how recognition of child abuse effective intervention could have changed John's story as he now sits on death row, Undated; nam_apap298-8_81 (Vhs 78)
  - Juan Raul Garza: Memorandum in Support of Petition for Clemency, Undated; nam_apap298-8_82 (Vhs 79)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #1 Planning for Fundraising, Kim Klein, Trainer 43:10, Undated; nam_apap298-8_83 (Vhs 80)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #2 The Role of the Board, Kim Klein, Trainer 40:50, Undated; nam_apap298-8_84 (Vhs 81)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #3 Raising Money by Mail, Kim Klein, Trainer 51:46, Undated; nam_apap298-8_85 (Vhs 82)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #4 Asking for Money and Prospect Identification, Kim Klein, Trainer 45:28, Undated; nam_apap298-8_86 (Vhs 83)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #5 Major Gift Solicitation, Kim Klein, Trainer 39:15, Undated; nam_apap298-8_87 (Vhs 84)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #6 Special Events, Kim Klein, Trainer 23:00, Undated; nam_apap298-8_88 (Vhs 85)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #1 Planning for Fundraising, Kim Klein, Trainer 43:10, Undated; nam_apap298-8_89 (Vhs 86)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #2 The Role of the Board, Kim Klein, Trainer 40:50, Undated; nam_apap298-8_90 (Vhs 87)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #3 Raising Money by Mail, Kim Klein, Trainer 51:46, Undated; nam_apap298-8_91 (Vhs 88)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #4 Asking for Money and Prospect Identification, Kim Klein, Trainer 45:28, Undated; nam_apap298-8_92 (Vhs 89)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Videotapes - Tape #6 Special Events, Kim Klein, Trainer 23:00, Undated; nam_apap298-8_93 (Vhs 90)
  - Growth Films [unlabeled VHS], Undated; nam_apap298-8_94 (Vhs 91)
  - HBO presents Clomic Stop Space Traders [?], Undated; nam_apap298-8_95 (Vhs 92)
  - Steve Hawkins, Undated; nam_apap298-8_96 (Vhs 93)
  - Steve Hawkins on Court-TV, Undated; nam_apap298-8_97 (Vhs 94)
  - Steve Hawkins on Fox News about Timothy McVeigh, Undated; nam_apap298-8_98 (Vhs 95)
  - Steve Hawkins Interviews 43:30, 1996 April 3; nam_apap298-8_99 (Vhs 96)
  - Interview with Mike Farrell: ABC interviews Mike Farrell on why he is opposed to the death penalty and his views toward the Mumia Abu Jamal case, 1994 April; nam_apap298-8_100 (Vhs 97)
  - Interview with Joyce Mokhesi: Mokhesi speaks about the case of the Sharpeville Six, Undated; nam_apap298-8_101 (Vhs 98)
  - Jessie Jackson "The Lethal Law": Former death row inmate Paula Cooper and four distinguished panelists debate the death penalty issue and examine its moral status, 1991 March 11; nam_apap298-8_102 (Vhs 99)
  - Journey of Hope: This tape gives an in-depth view of what JOH is all about, 1993; nam_apap298-8_103 (Vhs 100)
  - Journey of Hope: Not in My Name, 1995; nam_apap298-8_104 (Vhs 101)
  - Journey of Hope - Not in Our Names: A documentary of the Journey of Hope which travels across the country proclaiming the negative aspects of the death penalty in America, 1995; nam_apap298-8_105 (Vhs 102)
  - Justice on Trial: the Case of Gary Graham, 1993; nam_apap298-8_106 (Vhs 103)
  - Justice on Trial: the Case of Gary Graham - Addendum 7 Years Later, 1999; nam_apap298-8_107 (Vhs 104)
  - Juveniles, Undated; nam_apap298-8_108 (Vhs 105)
  - Les Couloirs de la Mort (The Colors of Death): A French documentary about the death penalty, 1996 November 16; nam_apap298-8_109 (Vhs 106)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience: 10 tapes - The Lighting the Torch of Conscience Movement involves organizing of religious leaders to campaign against the death penalty, Undated; nam_apap298-8_110 (Vhs 107)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_111 (Vhs 108)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_112 (Vhs 109)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_113 (Vhs 110)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_114 (Vhs 111)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_115 (Vhs 112)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_116 (Vhs 113)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_117 (Vhs 114)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated; nam_apap298-8_118 (Vhs 115)
  - Major Gift Solicitation: Kim Klein gives advice on how to solicit major gifts, Undated; nam_apap298-8_119 (Vhs 116)
  - Making Peace: A Moria Productions Series for The Independent Television Service, Undated; nam_apap298-8_120 (Vhs 117)
  - Making Society Safe: The Execution of Scum - SAD (Students Avocation Death) in Northern California explain the pros of the death penalty any why it should be used more often, Undated; nam_apap298-8_121 (Vhs 118)
  - Media Coverage of the John Wayne Gacy Execution: Several media stations covert he John Wayne Gacy execution, 1994 May; nam_apap298-8_122 (Vhs 119)
  - Arthur Miller Headlines on Trial: Should Juveniles Get the Death Penalty? - Victor Streib, Donna Hameperian, Daniel Popeo, and the Indiana State Prosecutor discuss whether it is morally right to send juveniles to death row, 1987 February 14; nam_apap298-8_123 (Vhs 120)
  - Ramon Montoya Excerpt: Excerpt of Montoya's body being received by thousands at Hidalgo, Texas, 1993 March 26-28; nam_apap298-8_124 (Vhs 121)
  - MSN-NBC "Death Penalty": Steven Hawkins is interviewed concerning the release of John Payne off of death row and the actions of Governor Allen, 1996 November 9; nam_apap298-8_125 (Vhs 122)
  - My Piece of Sky: A first hand look at death row from an inmate's point of view, Undated; nam_apap298-8_126 (Vhs 123)
  - NBC Nightly News - Shareef Cousin, 1997 December 2; nam_apap298-8_127 (Vhs 124)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the NCADP Annual Conference in New Orleans, Louisiana at Loyola University, 1986; nam_apap298-8_128 (Vhs 125)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Footage from the NCADP Annual Conference in New Orleans, Louisiana at Loyola University, 1986; nam_apap298-8_129 (Vhs 126)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the NCADP Annual Conference, 1987 November 14; nam_apap298-8_130 (Vhs 127)
  - NCADP Annual Conference - Bad Lawyering Workshop, Awards, Reception, 1987 November 15; nam_apap298-8_131 (Vhs 128)
  - NCADP Annual Conference - Opening: Footage of the opening ceremonies of the 1995 Annual Conference, nam_apap298-8_132 (Vhs 129)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Keynote Address by Ms. Mo-Janku Gumbi, South Africa & Awards Ceremony, 1995 August 5; nam_apap298-8_133 (Vhs 130)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Saturday Evening Banquet, 1995 August 5; nam_apap298-8_134 (Vhs 131)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: 1995 Meeting Audio Only, 1995 August 5; nam_apap298-8_135 (Vhs 132)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: KTVI-TV Channel 2 News at 6:03pm, 1998 October 2; nam_apap298-8_136 (Vhs 133)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the annual conference in St. Louis, Missouri, 1999; nam_apap298-8_137 (Vhs 134)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: 1999 Conference in Philadelphia, nam_apap298-8_138 (Vhs 135)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 1, 2001; nam_apap298-8_139 (Vhs 136)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 2, 2001; nam_apap298-8_140 (Vhs 137)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 3, 2001; nam_apap298-8_141 (Vhs 138)
  - News - Joseph O'Dell, Death Row Press Conference, Richmond, Virginia, 1996 July 24; nam_apap298-8_142 (Vhs 139)
  - News Coverage: Interview with Kevin Stanford, a death row inmate, and Stephen Bright, 1998 March; nam_apap298-8_143 (Vhs 140)
  - Nightline - Ted Bundy, 1989 January 23; nam_apap298-8_144 (Vhs 141)
  - Nightline - Mario Marquez execution, 1995 January 16-17; nam_apap298-8_145 (Vhs 142)
  - Nightline - Payne v. Tennessee, hanging and the death penalty, 1990 April 3; nam_apap298-8_146 (Vhs 143)
  - Off Center Productions, "A Pattern of Exclusion, The Trial of Thomas Miller-El" 13:30, 2002 February 4; nam_apap298-8_147 (Vhs 144)
  - One Life on the Edge - Jamie Elizalde, Jr. 26:00, 2005 October 8; nam_apap298-8_148 (Dvd 4)
  - One More Voice, produced and directed by Stephanie Gibson & Meg Heisse, 1998; nam_apap298-8_149 (Vhs 145)
  - "Paradise Lost" A special about 3 juveniles accused of killing 3 small boys, 1996; nam_apap298-8_150 (Vhs 146)
  - Peek v. State, 1985 October 7; nam_apap298-8_151 (Vhs 147)
  - Pittsburgh's Talking "Death Penalty": Sam Sheppard, Jr. of Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation discusses the organization and the case of his father, Sam Sheppard, 1990 June 8; nam_apap298-8_152 (Vhs 148)
  - Playwrite Express - '94: A play about a politician trying to become governor and his struggle to say he believes in the death penalty for votes when he actually he is an opponent, Undated; nam_apap298-8_153 (Vhs 149)
  - Politics and the Death Penalty: The question of whether rational discourse and due process can survive in the American political arena is examined, 1993 August 9; nam_apap298-8_154 (Vhs 150)
  - Sister Helen Prejean, Undated; nam_apap298-8_155 (Vhs 151)
  - Sister Helen Prejean speaking: Sister Helen Prejean speaks about her award winning book Dead Man Walking and shares her experiences as a spiritual advisor to many death row inmates, Undated; nam_apap298-8_156 (Vhs 152)
  - Racism and the Death Penalty: DPIC-Chattahoochee Report - ABC World News, Fox Morning News and the CNN World Report on racism and the death penalty, 1991 July 10-20; nam_apap298-8_157 (Vhs 153)
  - Reasonable Doubt: The case of Joe Giarratano, 1990; nam_apap298-8_158 (Vhs 154)
  - The Religious Community Confronts Death Penalty: This film discusses issues such as cost, revenge, deterrence, and racism 25:24, Undated; nam_apap298-8_159 (Vhs 155)
  - Reunion of Law Clerks and Research Associates of Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr. at Harvard University and the Judge's home - Part 1, 1998 May 2-3; nam_apap298-8_160 (Vhs 156)
  - Reunion of Law Clerks and Research Associates of Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr. at Harvard University and the Judge's home - Part 2, 1998 May 2-3; nam_apap298-8_161 (Vhs 157)
  - Rights for All-Amnesty International's Campaign on the USA, 1999; nam_apap298-8_162 (Vhs 158)
  - Rivera Live - On Capital Punishment: CNBC Geraldo Rivera discusses the death penalty, 1994 May 9; nam_apap298-8_163 (Vhs 159)
  - Darlie Router on Maury Povich, 1997 May 19; nam_apap298-8_164 (Vhs 160)
  - Should the Death Penalty be Abolished? Great Debate, 2002 November; nam_apap298-8_165 (Vhs 161)
  - Slideshow medly showing public action, Undated; nam_apap298-8_166 (Vhs 162)
  - Socialist Scholars Conference CUNY/NYC: Panel #72 Back on Death Row: A Reassessment of Capital Punishment in America with Bianca Jagger, Steven Bright, Kevin Doyle, 1999 April 11; nam_apap298-8_167 (Vhs 163)
  - Somebody Has to Shoot the Picture (HBO), 1990; nam_apap298-8_168 (Vhs 164)
  - Somebody Has to Shoot the Picture: HBO presents a film about an inmate who wishes to have still pictures of his execution taken, 1990; nam_apap298-8_169 (Vhs 165)
  - Southern Poverty Law Center: Historical View of the SPLC and what the organization hopes to move to, Undated; nam_apap298-8_170 (Vhs 166)
  - Stafford Smith Program, Undated; nam_apap298-8_171 (Vhs 167)
  - Stones: The Death Penalty Art Show, 2001; nam_apap298-8_172 (Vhs 168)
  - Texas Moratorium: Balancing The Scales 30 minute version, Undated; nam_apap298-8_173 (Vhs 169)
  - Texas Moratorium: Balancing The Scales 30 minute version, Undated; nam_apap298-8_174 (Vhs 170)
  - Thou Shall Not Kill, Undated; nam_apap298-8_175 (Vhs 171)
  - Thou Shall Not Kill: A biblical show that goes through scriptures of the bible to show that God forbids capital punishment, Undated; nam_apap298-8_176 (Vhs 172)
  - Too Flawed To Fix: The Illinois Death Penalty Experience, Peace Productions, Undated; nam_apap298-8_177 (Vhs 173)
  - Trial Story: Florida v. Ferrell, The Vampire Murderer, Court-TV, Undated; nam_apap298-8_178 (Vhs 174)
  - Tribute to Former Supreme Court Justice William Brennan: This video celebrates the work of anti-death penalty Supreme Court Justice William Brennan, 1994 November 10; nam_apap298-8_179 (Vhs 175)
  - University of Maryland Eastern Shore Panel on Capital Punishment, 1997 April 9; nam_apap298-8_180 (Vhs 176)
  - Various Interviews: Report on David Lawson and televised executions, ABC News a deep look at the case of Joe Burrows and his innocence, Report on lethal injections, Undated; nam_apap298-8_181 (Vhs 177)
  - Various News Coverage: ABC World News Tonight :To Live or Die", CBS 60 Minutes "Death Wish", ABC World News Sunday "Cost of the Death Penalty, Undated; nam_apap298-8_182 (Vhs 178)
  - Various News Shows: 20/20: Murderers fleeing to Abolitionist Countries, Eye on America: Battered Women who kill their partners, Niteline: Tennessee v. Payne, Undated; nam_apap298-8_183 (Vhs 179)
  - Various Programs: Fox Morning News, ABC World News Tonight, CNN Cable Network, News Channel 8, Undated; nam_apap298-8_184 (Vhs 180)
  - Victims families' & friends - "Don't Kill Me" Journey of Hop featuring Sister Helen Prejean, Undated; nam_apap298-8_185 (Vhs 181)
  - Virginia Currents: Host Rodger Coleman talks about current issues in Virginia, Undated; nam_apap298-8_186 (Vhs 182)
  - Voice of Democracy: Criminal Justice - Documentary on the news media effect on the publics view of crime, Undated; nam_apap298-8_187 (Vhs 183)
  - Who Killed Vincent Chin?, Undated; nam_apap298-8_188 (Vhs 184)
  - Whither Civil Rights, 35 Years After the Murder of Chaney, Schwerner and Goodman? - Committee on Civil Rights, Ronald J. Tabak (Program Moderator), Undated; nam_apap298-8_189 (Vhs 185)
  - Witches of Eastwick, Othello, The Charlie Rose Show: Ben Jealous talks about his 1997 Rhodes Scholar Award, Undated; nam_apap298-8_190 (Vhs 186)
  - Witness, Mark Landsman: Boods Not Bars, :30 second PSA, 3 minute PSA, 2000; nam_apap298-8_191 (Vhs 187)
  - Witness to the Execution: HBO presents a fictional movie about a televised execution, Undated; nam_apap298-8_192 (Vhs 188)
  - Working Films - Capital Punishment, Undated; nam_apap298-8_193 (Dvd 5)